Rutter McQuigg

rpmcquigg@gmail.com / (615) 870-9528 / http://linkedin.com/in/rutter-mcquigg-a691bb222

Driven sales and customer engagement professional with experience growing revenue and delivering exceptional customer experiences seeks sales role with technology and/or lifestyle brand where continually challenged and have opportunities for advancement of skills and responsibilities.

Prior Work Experiences

The Container Store (promoted to Full-time in April 2022)

Nashville, TN

October 2021 - May 2023 (Returning to school to study computer programing)

Project Specialist (Sales, Cashier, Order Processing, Inventory stocking, customer service)

- Represented the The Container Store experience as the first point of interaction with most customers
 - Zone-focused sales to drive growth of certain product groupings
 - Experience with cross-selling and up-selling promotions
 - Detailed benefits and signed-up customers for company loyalty program
 - Connected customers with product specialists for key product lines
 - Interacted with corporate and retail customers for sales
 - Processed retail sales (register), returns, and exchanges
 - Regularly closed sales between \$100-500 per transaction; Largest sale was \$2,000
- Provided customer service to assist customers and resolve product/service issues
 - Fielded and successfully resolved customers calls and inquiries
 - Responded to customer service issues (in-person and via phone) with goal of prompt, successful resolution
 - Review customer order history for reconciliation and returns/exchanges
 - Retail customer engagement greeted and directed customers
- Received and processed online orders for corporate and retail customers
 - Fulfilled online orders for in-store pick-up orders
 - Inspected orders for accuracy and product quality

- Communicated with customers about order status, unavailable/replacement products, and delivery timing
- Experience working in a team environment and as an individual contributor
- Experience working in an under-resourced environment while meeting sales and customer goals
- Tasks as assigned

Nashville Airsoft (Part-time)

Nashville, TN

Spring 2017 - Summer 2017 (Left to focus on high school)

Fall 2018 - Summer 2020 (Left to attend on college)

Summer 2021 (Left to seek new career opportunity, more hours)

Retail Store/Front Desk/Referee

- Represented the Nashville Airsoft experience as the first point of interaction with most customers
 - Responsibilities included selling and transacting customers' play experiences
 - Explained to customers how the play experience worked, rental equipment operations,
 and rules
 - Handled large group sales and coordinated their play experience
 - On average interacted with/sold experiences to 50 customers per day
 - Regularly closed sales between \$20-150 per transaction; largest sale was approximately
 \$500
 - Used point-of-sale system
- Closed sales for parties/events, making arrangements and reservations
 - Checked in and managed Scheduled parties/events, providing customer service to ensure a great experience
 - Regularly closed sales between \$150-350 per transaction; largest sale was approximately
 \$3,000
- Worked in retail store with responsibilities for selling equipment, gear, and supplies
 - Vast knowledge inventory and pricing for the majority of products sold
 - Regularly closed sales between \$50-250 per transaction; largest sales was approximately
 \$750
 - Used point-of-sale system
- Regularly fielded customer inquiries via phone, including making sales
- Experience working in a team environment and as an individual contributor
- Created personal relationships with many Nashville Airsoft regular and returning customers

- Experience selling annual memberships to customers
- General maintenance of equipment
- Tasks as assigned

ThriftSmart (Service Learning)

Nashville, TN

Spring 2018

Warehouse

Nashville Airsoft (Internship)

Nashville, TN

Spring 2017

Front Desk

Title Boxing (Internship)

Nashville, TN

Fall 2016

Front Desk

Education

Learning Lab Green Hills

Spring 2020

High School Diploma / GPA 3.8

Tennessee Technological University

Fall 2020

Completed one semester (left due to Covid impact on student life)

Nashville Software School

July 2023

3 week jumpstart program

Vanderbilt/edX Coding Boot Camp

August 2023 - February 2024

6 month web development program

Currently Enrolled

Technological Skills

Proficient - Apple iOS, Google Suite of apps, POS systems, Order fulfillment systemsExperience With - Windows, Microsoft Office Suite, Html, CSS, Java Script

Professional and Personal References Available Upon Request